Now, before we move to the architectural decisions, please remember building any production
grade genetic application is ultimately about balancing quality, latency and cost.
So, this is also sometimes called as the Gen Ai Trilema, where your objective is to build
the best quality application at lowest cost and low latency.
Now, if we just think about the use case that we just discussed on building Gen Ai
Power SME Assistant, which does the summarization for doing the summarization, we need
a foundation model or a large language model.
Now, just to help you correlate, if you have used chat GPT before and let us say you
send it a task to summarise a long document, it will use a foundation model or a large
language model behind the scene.
So, you can see here chat GPT is an application, but it uses GPT 5.2 model for doing
the task.
Now, the question is in AWS, which is the right service that provides you access to those
foundation models or large language models.
So, that is your first decision, choice of AWS service that provides you Gen Ai capability.
In AWS, there are two key services, one is Amazon Federal and it is the flagship AWS
service for Gen Ai, but we also have the SageMaker Jump Start.
And as we go along, we are going to deep dive into both Amazon Federal and SageMaker
Jump Start, look at the factors where we select Amazon Federal or SageMaker Jump Start.
Now, let us assume for a use case based on certain factors, you have selected Amazon
Betterock.
The next thing you have to do is select the right foundation model or the large language
model.
So, that is our second decision criteria, selection of the foundation model or the large
language model.
Now, we had selected Amazon Betterock, Amazon Betterock provides more than 100 different
models.
So, you will have models from Gemini, Cloud, Open Ai model from Amazon itself, Noa
Pro and so on.
So, you will need to think about what is your use case and what could be the right foundation
model.
So, we are going to look at all those considerations.
Now, let us say we selected the AWS service, we selected the foundation model and now
our end user, the SME sends the equipment images and issue logs to our foundation model
to do the summarization.
So, now even before this equipment data and logs etcetera go to this foundation model for
summarization, for large organizations, safety, security, responsible Ai is of critical importance
because they are subject to liability, repetition and so on.
So, sometime there is a possibility that a rogue employee may send some toxic content,
abuse you content to this foundation model or may ask, let us say question.
How do I rob a bank and foundation model can respond to that answer, if there are not
enough guardrails in place.
So, that is why having guardrails which not only filters the user input going to the foundation
model but also the response from the foundation model to build a safe responsible Ai application
and that is where our third decision comes into play on how you can implement the guardrails
safety and a responsible Ai principles and this is an extremely important topic not only
from exam but also from building the real world production grade application.
So, that is the third decision that you need to think about based on a use case what
could be the right set of guardrails and responsible Ai practices that you would implement.
Now, the next consideration you need to think about is the prompt engineering.
So, earlier we discussed about quality cost and latency.
So, how do we improve the quality of the response generated by the foundation model to the
equipment SME questions without increasing the cost and that can be done through prompt
engineering.
So, what prompt engineering allows you to do is create some reusable prompt templates
that can go along with the user input and in this case the equipment SME so that you
get an optimal response.
So here I just brought an example let us say the equipment SME sends these logs and then
just say summarize in 10 lines.
Then our system prompt what it can do is it can add some more context you can say you
are a manufacturing maintenance expert here is an example take a look at this example
and then summarize in 10 lines based on the new data and it will optimize the response
for you without substantially increasing the cost.
So, we are going to deep dive into this a little later.
So, next is the inference optimization there are different service tiers in Amazon bedrock
and based on your availability and cost needs you can select the right tier.
Then you also have cross region inferencing if your application is super critical then
you can choose cross region inferencing and we are going to discuss about all those things
but inference optimization is also an important parameter from the exam perspective so
you need to again you need to make those decisions to optimize for cost quality and latency.
Next we are going to look at cost optimization.
So how do you optimize the cost for your generative application and there are various techniques
to do that.
So you are prompt caching and there are some other techniques that we are going to discuss.
So, now next important decision that you need to make is what service are you going to
use for your generi orchestration layer.
So, you have multiple options so you have a lambda function, you have step functions
and you have ECS, EC2 and so on.
So, why do we need this generi orchestration layer?
Now think about all the things we said will go to the foundation model to generate a response.
So, the first one was is equipment logs issue logs and then the equipment SME said summarize
in 10 lines let us say then we added some guard rates which will block and it toxic content
and so on then we also said ok add some system prompts and here we had said you are a
manufacturing maintenance expert so and so on.
Now we need to orchestrate all of these things before this input is actually sent to the
foundation model and that is where our generi orchestration layer and most popular among them
is lambda function here because it is a much simpler use case but if it is more complex
then probably you are going to use step function.
So, we are going to look at all of this in detail but I am just for now as I said I am
just giving a mental model.
Now the 8 decision we have to make is on the API layer where we have the API gateway and
this is the most popular on the choice of API layer and we are going to deep dive into this
then we have ELB and apps thing so now let us say we have built the generi way application
and we have written a lambda function which sends the input to the foundation model but
we have to think about how do we securely expose our services to this end user how do
we authorize the end user how do we enable kotas how we do enable some form of throttling
so that all that is taken care of through this API layer so if you want expose your back
and services securely then you can do through this choice of API layer and the as I said
most model API gateway and we are going to deep dive into that later.
Okay next is the generi observability and monitoring so mainly you will do it through Amazon
CloudWatch now let us say you want to monitor your cost latency errors all that can be
done through Amazon CloudWatch and then you can set some alarms etc if they do not meet
certain threshold so Amazon bedrock allows you to monitor the logs and metrics through
direct integration with CloudWatch or you can also send those logs to S3 or both now the
10th decision is model evaluation so now let us say you have undertaken all these activities
and you build a great generi way application but the end user equipment SME is not happy
because it is not generating the desired results so that is why it is important to
evaluate your models before you start building full-fledged application and that is done through
model evaluation so Amazon bedrock provides your model evaluation capability which can be either
done through humans or automated evaluation now if you want to do some custom evaluation that
can be done through SageMaker AI so the 11 decision is on the model fine tuning again you have
SageMaker AI and Amazon bedrock available for model fine tuning so there could be
scenarios where let us say you build this generi way application and since the foundation model is
is trained on generate internet data let us say it is not able to correctly interpret the
wind turbine logs because it is domain heavy so in those scenarios you can customize your foundation
model either on the domain or specific tasks and in this scenario the task is chat so both Amazon
bedrock and SageMaker AI allow you for model fine tuning so next we have a very important topic
which is on security and data protection so there are different AWS service like cognitive, VPC
endpoint, KMS, Macy etc which allow you to secure your generi way services so here first one is the
user authentication authorization that can be done through Amazon cognitive if you are in an
enterprise settings then you can use NTRIID which was called as your AD earlier so you have to do
some form of authentication authorization then the second key aspect especially relative generi
AI is PI reduction so that you can either do through Macy there is comprehend there is Amazon
recognition and obviously there is Amazon guardrails so we are going to deep dive into all of these
services so you know in what scenario what kind of a service that you can use okay then we have
enterprise data management now let's say you are customizing your foundation model so for that
unit data let's say you are evaluating your foundation model again for that you will need to store
data in an AWS service and that's where you need to look at this enterprise data management whether
S3, FSX or any other relational or non-relational database then the 14 key responsible unit
to think about is gen A apps and governance for this generi way application how do you create
cloud formation template or CDK and then how do you deploy it through the pipeline how do you
register your models and then finally we have 15 we have the orchestration since this is relatively
simple application we are not going to look so much on the orchestration side but as we go
to the other use cases on rag and agents etc we will look at orchestration so there are different
ways in you can do complex orchestration either through some of the open source frameworks like
langchail, lang graph, your bedrock agents and so on but for now I just given you a mental model
of all the things you need to think about before building a production grid generi way applications
and please remember if you're not understood some parts of it it's okay I'm just giving you a
mental model we're going to detail out each of these topics in lot of detail as we go ahead
okay so that's pretty much it from this lecture I'll see you in the next lecture thank you